A Guide to the Publications from the Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, 1880-1987
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Publications from the Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, 1880-1987
The Library of Virginia
51423
8 cubic feet (8 boxes)
Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services,
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by the Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services. Accessioned 24 October 2014.
Biographical Information
On March 29, 1877, the General Assembly passed an act creating the Department of Agriculture, Mining, and Manufacturing to compile a geological handbook, analyze soils and fertilizers, dispense information to agriculturists in the state, and distribute seeds provided by the federal government. The Board of Agriculture was established by the General Assembly on March 5, 1888, to manage the department. The name of the department was changed to the Department of Agriculture and Immigration by an act passed on February 25, 1908, and the agency was given the additional mission of promoting the immigration of farmers into the state. On March 27, 1914, the General Assembly made the commissioner of the department a member of the Convict Lime Grinding Board. This board, which supervised the employment of state penitentiary convicts at state lime grinding plants, was abolished by the state government reorganization act passed by the General Assembly on April 18, 1927, and its duties were transferred to the Board of Agriculture and Immigration.
A major shift in focus occurred when, in a statewide referendum held on November 1, 1966, the voters approved a proposed constitutional amendment passed by the General Assembly on March 11 that changed the name of the department to the Department of Agriculture and Commerce. The governor issued a proclamation of the name change on November 30, 1966, and on March 4, 1971, the General Assembly passed an act codifying the change. The name of the department was changed to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services by an act passed by the General Assembly on March 24, 1978.
The Board of Agriculture and Consumer Services, which oversees the department, consists of eleven members, one from each congressional district. Seven of the members must be farmers. The members are appointed by the governor for four-year terms and confirmed by the Senate. The presidents of Virginia State University and Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University are ex-officio members of the board. The board is responsible for policy formulation on matters of agricultural and consumer concern.
Scope and Content
Publications of the Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, 1880-1987, include annual reports, bulletins, and federal Dept. of Agriculture yearbooks.
Arrangement
Publications are boxed by type.
Contents List
- Publications from the Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services, 1880-1987.
  - Agricultural Bulletin, Nos. 1-57, 1900 July-1911 May. (Box 4)
  - Agricultural Bulletin, Nos. 58-107, 1911 June-1915 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Agricultural Bulletin, Nos. 125-159, 1918 Jan-1920 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Agricultural Dairy and Food Division Bulletins, No. 21-29 (Executive), 1911 Dec-1913 May. (Box 4)
  - Agricultural Fertilizer Bulletins, Vol. 2, Nos. 58-107, 1911 June-1915 Dec. (Box 5)
  - Annual Report, Vol. 4, 1954-1955. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report, Vol. 4B, 1961-1965. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report, Vol. 5, 1966-1973. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report, Vol. 6, 1974-1978. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report, Vol. 7, 1980-1985. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report - Handbooks of Virginia, 1926-1931. (Box 5)
  - Annual Report of Sheep Husbandry for Virginia, 1881. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report of the Commissioner of Agriculture (4th), 1880. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report of the Commissioner of Agriculture, 1901. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report of the Dairy and Food Commissioner of Virginia (1st), 1908 June-1909 Mar. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report of the Dairy and Food Commissioner of Virginia (2nd), 1909 Mar-1910 Mar. (Box 6)
  - Annual Report of the Dairy and Food Commissioner of Virginia, 1915 Mar-1916 Mar. (Box 6)
  - Centennial Issues Bulletin, 1977 Mar-1978 Feb. (Box 5)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Nos. 22-43, 1905-1908. (Box 5)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 4, Nos. 160-180, 1921 Jan-1922 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 5, Nos. 184-206, 1923 Feb-1924 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 6, Nos. 208-228, 1925 Feb-1926 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 7, Nos. 210-252, 1927 Feb-1928 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 8, Nos. 254-276, 1929 Feb-1930 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 9, Nos. 278-300, 1931 Feb-1932 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 10, Nos. 301-322, 1933 Feb-1934 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 11, Nos. 323-344, 1935 Feb-1936 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 12, Nos. 345-366, 1937 Feb-1938 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 13, Nos. 367-388, 1939 Feb-1940 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 14, Nos. 389-410, 1941 Feb-1942 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 15, Nos. 411-432, 1943 Feb-1944 Dec. (Box 1)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 16, Nos. 433-458, 1945 Feb-1946 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 17, Nos. 459-475, 1947 Feb-1948 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 18, Nos. 498-497, 1949 Feb-1950 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 19, Nos. 498-519, 1951 Feb-1952 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 20, Nos. 520-541, 1953 Feb-1954 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 21, Nos. 542-563, 1955 Feb-1956 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 22, Nos. 564-585, 1957 Feb-1958 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 23, Nos. 586-607, 1959 Feb-1960 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 24, Nos. 608-628, 1961 Feb-1962 Nov. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 25, Nos. 629-643, 1963 Feb-1964 Apr. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 26, Nos. 644-659, 1964 May-1965 Sept. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 27, Nos. 660-678, 1965 Oct-1967 June. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 28, Nos. 679-700, 1967 July-1969 June. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 29, Nos. 701-722, 1969 July-1971 June. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 30, Nos. 723-744, 1971 July-1973 June. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 31, Nos. 745-763, 1973 July-1975 Mar. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. 31, Nos. 629-750, 1962 Dec-1973 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [32], Nos. 764-777, 1975 Apr-1976 June. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [33], Nos. 778-788, 1976 July-1977 June. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [34], Nos. 789-801, 1977 July-1978 Aug. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [35], Nos. 802-816, 1978 Sept-1979 Dec. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [36], Nos. 817-827, 1980 Feb-1981 Feb. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [37], Nos. 828-845, 1981 Mar-1982 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [38], Nos. 846-858, 1982 Oct-1983 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [39], Nos. 860-870, 1984 Feb-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [40], Nos. 871-881, 1985 Feb-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Monthly Agricultural Bulletin, Vol. [41], Nos. 882-902, 1986 Feb-1987 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Special Bulletins, Nos. 6-27, 1912-1913. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletins and Circulars, 1902-1916. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletins, Nos. 211-239, 1916 June-1925 Jan. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletins, Nos. 212-227, 1917 June-1924 Apr. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Truck Experiment Station Bulletins, Nos. 1-16, 1909-1915. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Truck Experiment Station Bulletins, No. 1-25, 1909-1917. (Box 5)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1905. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1907. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1909. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1910. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1911. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1912. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1913. (Box 7)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1914. (Box 8)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1915. (Box 8)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1916. (Box 8)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1917. (Box 8)
  - Yearbook of the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1919. (Box 8)